You don't find Bitcoin, Bitcoin finds
you. You don't find Bitcoin until you're
either personally or your business has
been so destructed that you can't get
out of a hole that you're looking for
something to park your money while you
figure out a plan. In his case, [music]
Bitcoin went higher, it allowed him to
do what he's done with strategy, but
that's why most people think this is a
scam. In my opinion,
>> What's going on, guys? Today's
conversation with Jordi Visser is a
great one. We talk about the slide down
in AI stocks, what happened with Ken
Griffin and Leopold and the entire book.
Then we go into what happened in Korea
and Japan and all the liquidations that
have happened there. We talk about Kevin
Warsh and the Federal Reserve and all
the interest rate decisions. And then of
course, we talk about crypto, Bitcoin,
Ethereum, much more. Today's
conversation with Jordi Visser is full
of insights I think you'll find very
valuable. So here's my latest
conversation with Jordi.
All right, Jordi, there's a huge week,
we got a lot to talk through. Let's
start with the unwind in AI stocks, uh
Leopold and situational awareness. They
basically are forced to sell uh their
entire book, it sounds like. Um you've
lived through a couple of these unwinds.
What are your takeaways given what's
transpired over the last week or so?
>> Well, I guess there's um
there's two parts to this. And yeah, I I
was in Brazil
uh in 1997 and 1998 into '99.
And I was uh
I was a part of the LTCM
uh unwind. I was a part of the true
unwind, meaning I came back to the US in
the beginning of '99 and I took over the
S&P book.
And
later on in 2007,
uh I was managing a portfo- a macro
portfolio
uh during the quant unwind, which was
really a garp unwind, which was during
the great financial crisis, but very
early. And then I would even say
Archegos or Archegos or whatever the
name he had for his thing that blew up
in 2021.
I've been through a bunch of these and
uh
here's the most important thing and I
don't think I've seen this in in the
news yet in terms of the way it's
written.
So, the one interesting thing about
leverage in the hedge fund world is
eventually when you get to the end,
meaning where you've had a drawdown and
that is so significant,
you have to try and find buyers for your
portfolio or it needs to be liquidated.
And that happened in all three of those
scenarios. And once that starts to
happen,
where you start needing to either call
people up or your prime brokers know
everything and they're calling people,
which is normally what happens cuz the
prime brokers at the investment banks
are the lenders of these and once
they're involved,
everyone starts to see the portfolio,
they look at their own risk and say,
"Where am I exposed?" And they start
hedging. So, the one thing I want to
want to make sure people know, um
this was a cleansing event in my
opinion. Uh it doesn't mean that we're
not going to see continued volatility,
but what he went through
is a situation where you start losing
money mainly because of the reasons I
talked about the AI mid-cycle slowdown,
which is
when things become too crowded and
everyone has the same positions. And
especially when you're dealing with
someone who got all of this fame from
making so much money and you could see
his positions reported in 13F holdings
and he hasn't been through this before
and he believes in the fundamentals,
stock prices diverge from fundamentals
all the time. We saw that with
Liberation Day last year. You can have
the stock market fall 20% and nothing
change economically, nothing change
earnings-wise, and it can snap back just
as fast. So, the AI trade to me, um
started getting narratives about
Anthropic's in trouble, uh
the hyperscalers are in trouble, uh
we're never going to get the revenues,
uh open source, all of these things.
Every week it was a new thing that we
had to talk about when the reality is
for the month of July we saw a record
factor unwind.
It took down
Leopold to a level that he needed to get
out of his portfolio. What we don't know
all the true story about is
when did Citadel find out? When did
Millennium find out? I bring this up
because these were the names that were
reported in the paper and once they see
things they have exposure to this as
well. So there was a four-day move
beginning on Friday of last week.
Uh into this week with the final part
being in in the 2 hours after the Fed.
And to me that was basically an enormous
amount of people that were not only
liquidating his portfolio but making
sure that they were reducing their risk
and then using his positions to allow
them to be in a better position coming
out of this. So for everyone who's
watching this who's wondering, well,
what's going on? This is markets.
And as I've talked about one of my
themes is more bubbles, more parabolas,
and more speed crashes and we just lived
through \quote} \unquote}
a mini bubble
that you could see through a parabola
and now we've had a speed crash and
remember, no matter how fast markets go
up in a bubble, they look like you're
going upstairs during it and then you
fall down the elevator shoot on the way
down and I think that's what happened
>> and over the course of this month.
Do you think that Citadel knew he was in
trouble and so this like surprise Fed
hike story, was that like a potentially
intentional way to put him in a bad
position or is that just the internet
putting on the tin foil hat and trying
to draw a good story?
>> We'll never know.
Um
it helped the case. Um you know,
I I did a
mid mid-week video this week where I
went through number one, the the the
losses that happened before these four
days. So, Leopold's losses, they were
not caused by him either being reached
out to by Ken Griffin or reaching out to
these places or through the prime
brokers.
Um
the losses were happening because there
was going to be a correction and things
don't go straight up. Uh I think what he
got caught into is the losses were
compounding so fast and so many people
had on the same trades that it reached a
point where he needed to find something
or he could be out of business. And I
think whether it was the hyperscaler
earnings reports, whether it was the
fears that the Fed were going to raise
rates. I will say this, there's a lot of
press that Citadel came out and said
they'd raise rates. There were other
people that thought they would raise
rates. The probability was close to 40%.
Um so, it's not like they caused this
and I don't think we'll ever know
whether that's the case, but I do think
when you have someone that is uh
suffering and heading towards
a catastrophe, uh it seems like he was
able to get out of this with significant
gains still on the year and be able to
cleanse his book. But, the reality is
we'll never know the answer to your
question.
>> When um
when you look at his performance, it's
now rumored that he was up like 400%
um and through the month of June, uh he
had like $25 billion
in the hedge fund that he started I
don't know, two, three years ago. Um it
is objectively one of the
um kind of craziest runs I think someone
has had in starting a hedge fund uh over
the last couple of decades. Being down
80%, 70%, you know, whatever the number
actually is, still means he may have
like $10 billion
sitting in the fund. So, if you were um
a potential LP or maybe somebody who was
evaluating whether you'd go work there,
does put him in like a negative light
and people say, "Hey, you know, he's
he's a failed hedge fund manager.
Everyone's going to run away." Or are
people going to be like, "Look, now we
got a guy who's obviously skilled, he's
got a chip on his shoulder, just got a
great reminder about risk mitigation,
and so maybe now's actually the most
attractive time, and he may, you know,
go put up really good numbers."
>> I I I think um that whole conversation
is uh
I I've learned throughout my years of
people being able to raise money. If you
produce returns, people will give you
money. Um out of the 10 billion, I mean,
it's being reported that about 5 billion
of that is private
an anthropic position. Um so I I don't
know how much money he raised. I don't
know what went on. I'm sure he did take
in money. I think it's very hard to come
back from a scenario where you're 25
years old and you're talking about
you've just had a learning experience,
which is what was reported in the the
letter that he sent out. Um I think it's
going to be really hard for large people
to give him money um on this. I'm sure
there were people that were using his
knowledge as well
uh for what to invest in. So
I Th- This is a different thing, and I
don't know how much we've talked about
it, but you know, the market structure
is changing, and
we've met, you and I, uh
around the nexus of AI and crypto.
I like to spend my time on AI. I'll keep
saying over and over again for anyone
who wants to go to my my YouTube and
watch that
compute demand will be outstripping
supply for a long time.
And along that journey, unfortunately,
we're going to see a lot of what we've
seen this year. So let's go back and
recap.
We saw a collapse in software stocks at
the beginning of the year.
It spread into other sectors. Everyone
was worried that the terminal value of
companies, you couldn't value them 3
years from now.
That's a fact.
Hedge fund leverage was at all-time
highs to begin the year, and according
to data in the papers, Goldman Sachs
said it was the largest increase in
gross exposure that they had seen in any
5-month period in history.
If all of that is true, and I believe it
is, hedge fund leverage was going up at
a time when terminal value, or being
able to value a company in 3 years, is
going down.
I think what we saw with Leopold, and
what we're going to see with the entire
market,
is a structural change. AI agents are
getting more involved in
decision-making. There's more optimized
portfolios, because it's very easy to go
in and do that. Robinhood just put out
another agentic tool this week that
allows people sitting at home to
immediately get technical indicators
immediately from AI agents.
The game is speeding up, and so
innovation's changing. We're going
through a period where everything is
speeding up dramatically, and what used
to take 30 years is now taking 3 years.
And that means that for the entire
financial markets, but in particular
hedge funds that borrow money,
generally have quarterly liquidity, and
they're making investments in things at
sizes on leverage that they couldn't get
out of in a short amount of time if they
wanted to, and positions are getting
more crowded than ever, which is why
we've seen the largest momentum unwind
in history. The market structure is
changing, and I don't think leverage is
ever going to go back to the highs. So,
in the same way that I've said
repeatedly, which has been the case this
year,
earnings growth in the S&P 500
is above 20%. The S&P is not on pace to
be up over 20% for the year. We've seen
multiple compressions so far.
I think we're going to see the same
thing in leverage. So, my belief is that
for public equities and for hedge funds,
there's going to be a
a scenario where
speed crashes are going to happen more
often. We're going to see more events
like Leopold. It's going to force people
and prime brokers to not extend as much
leverage as they used to. So, not only
are indices going to see multiple
compression, but you're going to see
more and more of these extreme cases
within side uh hedge funds.
>> Let's talk about uh Korea and Japan. I'm
going to read you a couple of
statistics. So, uh South Korea's stock
market collapsed 45% in about 40 days
and erased $2 trillion in market cap.
Then, in South Korea, there was about
1.2 million leveraged retail trading
accounts that got triggered on margin
calls as of July uh mid-July or so. And
then if you go and you look in uh Japan,
there's about $200 billion that was
wiped out uh in the Japanese stock
market um in a single day when it
dropped, you know, nearly 3%. And so,
when I see that,
my initial take is that, "Hey, we live
in this interconnected world and if the
US is seeing, you know, drawbacks,
um obviously other markets are likely
they are, too." But, when I read the
statistics around South Korea and the
leveraged retail trading accounts, that
feels like it is very unique to that
geography versus the United States. How
do you read the impact that, you know,
the Asian markets can have on the US?
>> Well, first of all, um
Korea's up 56% year to date.
So, in the same way that Leopold um
had a huge drawdown needed to be bailed
out, according to the data we have,
he's still up 80% year to date, I
believe, based on what I saw today. Um
the Korean market, you just named how
big the correction is, but their
market's up 56% year to date. The S&P
500 is up about 8% year to date.
I I just think that um AI is allowing
people, because of the speed, to jump
into things and trends because
fundamentally
I mean
where Samsung, where SK Hynix, where
Micron are trading
I mean they're trading at multiples that
mean people are already building in the
end of this cycle at some point because
they're cyclical companies and so I
think people were buying these because
they had a math behind it. Um, again,
for everyone who's who's watching this
who has more of a trad-fi mentality and
and less about Bitcoin
I believe the market is going through
over the course of the next five years
AI will destroy all public companies.
And when I say destroy, it will destroy
the growth certainty of all companies
going forward and that's why multiples
should come down. It's not that
companies will go out of business, it's
that you won't be able to know whether
you have a company that will survive
because it will be eaten away by AI
native startup businesses that have much
more margins in their business and are
able to compete on everything that you
do. It will take time to get there. The
physical constraints allow Micron and
Samsung and SK Hynix to be able to have
again, scarcity and that's why the
Korean market was in there, but I do
think the mentality of margins is very
different in the Korean market than it
is in the US market, but remember too
the US market has gone through a secular
bull market where from 2007
the S&P has produced over 15% a year
while the rest of the world has only
seen equities break out above their 2007
levels as a whole
over the course of the last three years.
That's the difference, Anthony, is that
you're getting people that are getting a
taste of a bull market they haven't seen
in a long time. On the US, people have
been involved in this they don't need
the leverage as much because the
household net worth in the country is
over 180 trillion dollars.
>> Now, speaking of leverage, um people may
think of it a little bit differently,
but the large hyperscalers, they are
dipping into their free cash flow. Uh
they've been taking on some debt.
Um they are not speculating necessarily
on day-to-day, you know, stock prices,
but they are making a big bet uh they're
going to see an ROI from uh from the
CapEx investment. Um Door Dash had a
great uh piece this week that um I know
you've got some thoughts on. What was
your takeaway from his piece?
>> Um his piece I I'm going to cover a lot
over the weekend. I thought it was great
and it it kind of took a uh
a contrarian bend in one side and it got
into this thing of
there really being concentrated winners
and you can make this case for both
Anthropic and OpenAI, but you can also
make it for the hyperscalers. Um I don't
think this is going to happen,
but his argument [clears throat] really
got into the fact against something that
people have talked about, which I happen
to agree with. So, his argument was that
in the case of Anthropic and OpenAI,
they're actually going to control even
more
of AI than people realize because
they're going to be the only ones that
are going to be able to have the compute
and offer it out to people and that the
most valuable things are going to want
tokens per watt. And this is the thing
that gets really efficient. If we never
get to the point or if it takes us a
long time to get to the point where
compute lines up on the supply side with
demand, we're going to have a problem
and the analogy that I'm using in over
the weekend is what happens to
the way people think about buying a car
if gas at the pump is a dollar versus at
$10 a gallon. So, at a dollar per
gallon, people don't mind buying gas
guzzlers. They're cheaper than more
expensive cars, but if it's $10 a gallon
and now a car is 50% more for an
efficient car that gets 40 miles to the
gallon as opposed to 10-mi to the
gallon, more people are going to go for
that efficient car because it makes more
sense. And that's what's going to
happen, and the company that I just want
to use as an example is Disney.
How much is the compute available? If
there was only a finite of night of
a finite amount of compute that
Anthropic could offer to
all of the companies in the world, and
let's assume, just to make it simple, it
was a number, and they had 100 gigawatts
worth of compute. And Disney came in and
said, "I want all of that compute, and
I'm willing to pay you a trillion
dollars for that compute."
And everyone else is only willing to pay
100 billion dollars, and Anthropic goes,
"Fine, you get that compute, and no one
else gets compute."
The reason Disney would be wanting to do
that is because the most token-hungry
scenario is video. So, let's assume they
wanted to make a movie that instead of
costing 3 billion dollars would cost 50
million.
But, they can go out and sell it at the
prices that will bring in revenues. So,
their revenues per token,
they're willing to pay more money for
because they have the distribution.
This is what his argument is, is that
because the supply of compute is just
nonexistent, and every day the
capabilities are getting better,
people are going to want that. Now, the
argument on the other side for why the
hyperscalers are at risk and all of this
stuff is the fact that people believe
that you'll never be able to get the
revenues in. But,
if you can sell something at a price
because there isn't the deflation, if
Disney can sell movie tickets at $20 a
seat,
and no one else can
underprice that, and now they have this.
Well, this is why Micron is having
margins now at levels that we've never
seen in memory because they have
scarcity of it. Compute scarcity is a
reality, and I don't care what anyone
says all the CDS on the hyperscalers and
all of this, we just went through
Amazon, Microsoft, and Google now.
And the total sum of their backlog of
contracted orders is nearing 2 trillion.
If you add in Oracle, you're over 2
trillion. And they all said the same
thing on their calls, which I'm going to
go through.
We have
orders to match up with our CapEx. So,
they didn't cut CapEx, they overall
raised CapEx.
Basically, assuming it was in line with
all the price changes. I just think that
when you read the Dwarkesh article, he's
making a very contrarian spin, which
Gavin Baker echoed as well, which is
if there's a finite amount of compute,
the company that is able to deliver the
most efficient models, which is what
Anthropic and Open AR, they're going to
take the big orders from everyone
because they've also been the ones smart
enough to secure the compute available.
This goes against the open-source story,
it goes against everything. And I happen
to believe that it's going to show up in
the ARR numbers for Anthropic and Open
AI until that's not the case, and I
don't know when the compute supply is
going to get close to demand because
demand just is accelerating.
>> So, let's say that he is right on this.
Then, you go and you look at um
Microsoft
XAI or SpaceXAI.
Um you look at
uh Meta,
Google.
I mean, these people have enormous
access to compute.
Why are some of them opening up their
compute to others? Do they just not need
as much as they've actually built? And
then also, does that mean if they have a
more access to compute than Anthropic or
Open AI does,
actually, you know, Open AI and
Anthropic are at a disadvantage compared
to these large guys who can catch up?
>> Well, let let's go through the
difference between um who's who's
offering up their compute and who's
gobbling up the compute. Open AI and
Anthropic are not offering out compute.
They are the gobblers. They are the ones
eating everything.
Um
XAI or SpaceX is offering compute
because he doesn't need it right now.
He's going to need it eventually for his
humanoids and full self-driving and
everything else that he's going to have.
On the other side with Meta, Meta cares
about personal agents and he cares about
the fact that the agents that they're
going to need, the demand is much
bigger. Sam Altman gave an interview
with Patrick O'Shaughnessy on Invest
Like the Best. He specifically talked
again about something that I show in my
videos every single weekend, which is we
are still in the I mean, we're not even
out of the first out in the first inning
of the agentic needs for inference. All
we're doing so far are the coding
agents. The personal agents we haven't
got to. Until people can speak into
a pin, their phone, something with an AI
model that is able to talk back like
Siri, do things
that we want it to do. Siri doesn't work
yet. Alexa doesn't work yet.
If you're in a bad um cell spot, you
can't actually use
uh your Open AI on your phone in a way
that allows you to go through it. It
needs to be on the phone.
That means the hardware needs the
memory. We're in this situation where
again, I can't I can't say it loud
enough to people, we just don't have the
hardware and the capabilities to get the
AI to everything that we need. So, the
demand is going. There are ways
for sure that supply will catch up with
demand.
But, that is not even close to what's
happening. So, there will be algorithmic
efficiency impacts and Sam Altman talks
about all of these in the interview with
Patrick O'Shaughnessy, but he literally
says, "We underestimated the amount of
supply." And this is Open AI, which has
arguably been the most aggressive
spender of this and because they
underestimated it, think about
Anthropic. Anthropic underestimated big
time. Dario Modi was warning everyone
about the ROIC last year that you're
taking a huge bet. He was betting that
OpenAI was going crazy and now you know
what Dario's thinking? Oh my god, I wish
I would have more. Luckily for him,
SpaceX and Meta have built so much that
in the case of SpaceX, SpaceX not only
sold it to
Anthropic,
they also sold capacity to Google.
Google's a major cloud provider that
doesn't have enough capacity and their
Gemini, they haven't made a major model
and they were one of the leaders on
this. So everyone underestimated the
amount of supply of compute that was
necessary and this comes while every
investor who's worried, who sends me an
email,
is telling me that we've overbuilt, that
we're not getting the revenues in when
every single smart person that's
involved with building this stuff and
seeing the demand is saying they can't
keep up with it.
>> Today's episode is brought to you by
Figure Markets. All right, everyone, who
wants a slice of $160,000?
Our partner, Figure's running a promo
where they're giving back to their
community. From July 27th to August
27th, 1 month, any users who've never
completed a crypto-backed loan with them
can qualify. You can check out the link
in my bio for more information. If you
believe in Bitcoin long-term like me,
the worst move you can make is selling
it while it's down just to access
liquidity. That's why you should check
out Figure. Right now, Figure offers
crypto-backed loans at 8.91% interest
with 50% LTV. So you can unlock capital
without triggering taxes or giving up
your Bitcoin exposure. Figure's already
the largest non-bank HELOC lender in the
United States [music] with over $22
billion unlocked for homeowners. They've
spent years helping people tap into
their home equity without selling their
house and now they're letting Bitcoin
holders do the exact same thing.
Security matters here. Figure uses
[music] decentralized MPC custody,
meaning that your Bitcoin stays in a
segregated wallet. It isn't
rehypothecated, it isn't pooled, and it
doesn't sit on an exchange balance
sheet. They've also rolled out
liquidation protection to help protect
borrowers against liquidations and
margin calls related to price movement
during sharp market drawdowns. And if
you're stacking sats, but also want
yield, Democratize Prime lets retail
investors earn up to 9% APY paid hourly
back by real-world assets,
>> [music]
>> not yield gains or token inflation. Hold
your Bitcoin, unlock liquidity, and put
capital to work.
>> [music]
>> Check out Figure using my link below, or
go to figuremarkets.co/pomp.
>> It's funny because it's almost like
Elon's too good at building, you know,
and
compute. He's too good at building
energy. That's why he's been able to
outbuild what he needs, whereas
everybody else, maybe they misjudged how
much they would need, but also, you
know, if you put Elon up next to Google
and said go, you both have to build, you
know, 100 megawatts or you know,
whatever, who would get it done faster?
I think Elon, you know, beats almost
every single person in the world.
>> Well, this is one of the things that to
me, if there's one takeaway from this
week that people should have, go back
and read Leopold's 2027 situational
awareness paper.
He's been spot-on
about where things would be.
He talked about AGI being here by 2027,
the government getting more involved
with the company. All of these things
are actually happening. If anything,
they're happening slightly faster than
he expected. I think with this whole
thing proves, with the excess capacity
of xAI, with the excess capacity of
Meta, with Sam Altman saying he
underestimated, with Dario Amodei is
scrambling to find compute from
anywhere,
the smartest people involved with AI all
underestimated one thing.
And this is the human being side.
The danger with what happened with Dario
Modai, if you go back and listen to his
arguments last year about what Sam was
doing,
his argument was we're not seeing the
adoption at the pace that we expected.
And that had to do with human beings and
enterprises. What surprised everyone was
the enterprises picking up the pace. The
reason this is important for everyone to
matter, and this gets heavily into
what's going to happen over the next 12
months with crypto.
Everyone underestimates how quickly that
the agentic world
brings humans with it.
Agentic movement happens fast. The
thing people can't comprehend is what it
means to have AI agents doing
everything. That's what's happening
within inside enterprises for workflows
is the agents are figuring out how to do
this. Once we get into the point where
you use Leopold and you say, "Hey, if
you wanted to compare something with
Leopold and you had to find, you said
the fastest or the best hedge fund from
the start, arguably Bitcoin is the best
hedge fund ever.
Its returns look like Leopold's. We have
corrections. Leopold gave up what, 70,
80% of his gains? Well, Bitcoin at the
very early start gave up 70, 80% of its
gains, has continued to compound. Why
did you have trouble getting all of the
famous people, investors that you
mentioned over the course last decade to
invest in Bitcoin where they threw you
out of their office. All of these
stories that you have,
it was because they knew better. These
types of returns don't happen. In the
hedge fund world, if you walk in and
you're Leopold and you show I'm making
this much money, "Okay, great. I'll give
you tons of money." We saw this happen
with Melvin Capital. We saw this happen
with everything. It's about your past
performance, which is not indicative of
future returns. What AI agents are going
to look like, they're not going to look
look at this and say, "I don't believe
in Bitcoin." They're going to look at
the returns and go, okay, let me
discount this. Let me put some
probability that it's a it's a new
asset. I won't give it all of my money,
but what I will do is put 5%, 10%, 15%,
20%. And those people that have 0% once
agents start making decisions for them,
the same thing that we've seen with the
adoption here, the adoption of crypto
will go through the roof when AI agents
are more involved in transactions and
more involved in investing.
>> Kevin Warsh
he he stole the show by doing nothing.
I think everyone was pontificating which
actually about Citadel saying there's a
surprise rate hike. I think with the
cooling inflation, there's just a lot of
moving parts here. And so they decided
to just kick can down the road. Agree or
disagree with their decision.
>> Uh well, I agree with their decision. Um
I actually like what Kevin Warsh is
doing. Um
I I believe using old academic models is
going to be a problem. This is one of
the reasons why the hedge fund leverage
situation is going to come down. There's
a reason why and I'm going to show some
charts which are going to show people
how structurally the stock market has
completely changed. For those of you who
who care about factor risk, I will go
through a lot of charts on factor
volatility, on S&P volatility, on Nasdaq
volatility, comparing them all on single
name volatility versus index volatility.
The market's changing and the market's
changing because of AI. Kevin Warsh is
saying the Fed needs to change because
of AI. If you're using the prior three
months of data in a world that is now
every month is equivalent to three
months or 30 months,
if everything is 10 times what it used
to be in terms of the speed,
how can you use inflation data from
yesterday to make decisions other than
from the psychological basis of dealing
with humans? Well, in the case of what
the market reacted, we got a steepening
of the yield curve when he basically
said,
"Well, we didn't really need to do
anything because
you guys wanted a tightening and the
market has tightened for us. 10-year
rates have gone up, 2-year rates have
gone up. So, really the market already
did did it for us while inflation came
back down a little bit. So, we got time
to wait for inflation and see where it
is."
I think this new no forward guidance
going into the meeting, people had a 40%
chance of a tightening, where in the
past there'd have to be an article
released beforehand to be a tightening.
I think this is going to add more
volatility into the system and more
uncertainty. So, it gets back to the
point I made about leverage. If the Fed
was also contributing to the leverage in
the system through QE, meaning whenever
assets fell, they would grow their
balance sheet, he wants to shrink his
balance sheet. Well, that means he wants
the Fed to be less levered. All of this
leads to the same conclusion, which is
there's going to be less leverage in the
system. And as tokenization comes, which
I believe he and Bessant have both
talked about,
tokenization will release money supply
in a way
that will allow the Fed to delever at
the same time. That's what I believe is
going to happen is that AI agents and
tokenization will allow dormant assets,
which are just sitting there but have a
value,
to be monetized in a way in daily
liquidity and in transactions through
pieces of them in fractionalization. And
I think once that happens, the Fed won't
be needed as much and I think him and
Bessant both believe this as people that
believe in crypto and Bitcoin.
>> Do you think it's a good idea for the
Fed to get delevered?
>> Yeah, I I well, I think it's going to
happen and I do. I think it's going to
help the distribution of wealth problem.
So, I I think um the K-shaped economy
has been formed because of the leverage
of the balance sheet. I think since the
great financial crisis to to avoid a
great depression, they had to use their
balance sheet whenever there was a
problem. We have a financialized stock
market. But right now, it doesn't seem
like we need those tools the way we did
in the past. One is there's not as much
leverage and the leverage that is
growing where CDS is going wider is on
the best balance sheets in the world,
the hyperscalers. That's why I'm not
worried about them. Their CDS should be
going higher because clearly the markets
are having a trouble having trouble
providing the capital on a short-term
basis that's come to the market. I think
one thing people need to recognize is
that SpaceX comes to the market. Plus
there's a lot of lockup that's coming in
that's going to hit the market. You've
got Anthropic, you've got OpenAI, you've
got all of them raising money for CapEx
for these things. We're tapping the
market in big size. Google did an $80
billion
These things have never happened before.
It takes a while for this kind of
capital coming to the market to be
digested and I think that's what we've
seen in AI as all this has gone on. So I
think the Fed balance sheet will help
the K-shaped economy. I think you have
to look at this the way Kevin Warsh
does. He's not saying he's going to
shrink the balance sheet in the next
year.
He's saying opportunistically when he
can, he wants this stuff to come down.
But it would also happen with rates
coming down. So I think when he's
comfortable on inflation and when the
labor market is soft enough, I think
you're going to see rate cuts combined
with the balance sheet being run down a
little bit.
>> When we look at
um the impact that this would have on
uh stock market, on Bitcoin, on gold,
many of these different assets,
um
is that something that investors should
be excited about? Or is this a situation
where if you want to help Main Street,
you know, Wall Street suffers? You want
to help Wall Street, Main Street
suffers.
>> So again, I'm going to go back to what I
said. I think over the course of the
next 5 years, the most important force
that's going to happen is AI. So let's
just assume that everyone starts with
one number.
And just assume this number is true that
the total
household net worth of the planet Earth
is about $700 trillion
and the total value of crypto is about 3
trillion.
So we've all heard, and this is the way
I value crypto. What I think will happen
over time is that that total value will
either stay the same overall. So it's
let's say 703 trillion. 700 trillion in
non-crypto, 3 trillion in crypto.
Let's assume in 5 years it's still 703
trillion.
What I believe will be happening is that
the money will be redistributed. Now
some of that will go into crypto.
Um in terms of this. The main point is
I believe small businesses win in AI. So
let's assume the winners of the the
stock market, the companies that win the
revenues, they're all AI native.
Well, the AI native businesses grow
bigger, but a lot of these AI native
businesses are like my business, like
Cursor, like Anthropic, like OpenAI.
Meaning they're AI native businesses
with very few employees. They own the
majority of their business. Not in the
case maybe of OpenAI and Anthropic, but
of most private companies, the founders
are going to own most of their business.
And let's assume it only goes to
a $100 million business. Well, in the
past that $100 million business
needed to go to 5 billion, and I don't
think that's going to be the case
anymore. And the founder is going to own
75%. So crypto's going to end up being
say $100 trillion in a decade.
The rest of the assets of the world will
still be 603 trillion, and will still be
around the same overall number. There'll
be a transfer, and then within the 600
trillion, I think the public stock
markets
will be effectively unchanged, and
private businesses will grow in their
valuations, and you'll be able to access
these through ETFs that are tokenized
that give you every asset in the world.
And that's what the future is going to
look like. And as someone who ran ETFs
at Morgan Stanley back in the late or
for early 2000s,
I can just tell you that nobody believed
in ETFs back in 2000. Now, it's an
accepted thing that dominates the
market. Tokenization is a massive change
to the structure of the market. AI
agents are a massive change, and all of
this stuff is coming. It's a certainty.
It's not an not even an if. It's not a
when anymore. It's happening, and it's
happening this
>> Based on all of your experience and
seeing these different technology trends
or different that kind of asset
structures go from not popular or
contrarian to consensus and popular. Uh
let's say that you were 25 years old
just starting your career. What would
you do in able to benefit from this
trend? Whether you were starting a
business or going and looking for a job,
like how would you position yourself
given everything you've seen in the past
to
um get the tokenization trend as the
maybe a tailwind?
>> Well, ETFs
the changing of products or structures
didn't impact in my opinion the overall
situation. It hurt business It hurt
mutual funds. Um it obviously changed
stock ownership, meaning BlackRock has
been a big winner, but it's not like
they've gone parabolic. I I think the
way to have made money since ETFs came
out
really was about
innovation and which companies were
going to dominate. You're basically
betting on where moats will be. Um
Warren Buffett made money on investing
in moats. Um the Mag 7
have moats. Now, their stock prices
have not moved over the last year for
the hyperscalers. We're seeing multiple
compression, but right now I'm trying to
invest in scarcity because I think we're
at the phase of innovation where we
can't actually produce
the energy necessary. So, we're
converting, as David Friedberg said in
the podcast this past weekend, we're
con- converting molecules into bits, and
I want to be involved in the molecule
side right now. And that's why I focus
my attention on scarcity. So, scarcity's
not just Bitcoin. Scarcity is Micron.
Scar- Scarcity is um
GE Vernova. Scarcity is all of these
things that are necessary to build out
the compute that are still going to have
the earnings growing. Their multiples
can compress, and this is the thing
people have to understand. Just because
you're making money,
I believe in multiple compression
because even for these companies that
are based on scarcity, in 3 years, when
humanoids are a reality, and they're
making it cheaper for every physical
business, meaning they're involved in
building buildings and being involved in
in the uh the
uh the semiconductors,
including all of the intelligence at the
level. I think all businesses and ideas
will be disrupted, and that means you
have to get into the only thing that
gets hurt the least. And that's the
thing that I want to make sure people
realize. If you don't believe in
Bitcoin, you have to go back at some
point uh and go listen to the Michael
Saylor interviews in 2021 about why why
he did this. He did this because of two
forces that were hurting him. One was
competitive innovation. His business had
a billion dollars on the on the balance
sheet, but he could not compete with the
size of Microsoft and the bus- the the
competition was just not there. And this
was after the Mag 7 had come to
existence. He talks about it all the
time. So, one was he lost to innovation.
Number two,
he was now losing to the basement from
the government. They had moved rates
down to zero. So, he had a successful
business with a billion dollars of
balance sheet, but with very, very
difficult in terms of making money. So,
he made a decision to invest in
something that was
going to be defendable versus
debasement. I think where Bitcoin comes
in is the same the quote that he uses
all the
You don't find Bitcoin, Bitcoin finds
you. You don't find Bitcoin until you're
either personally or your business has
been so destructed that you can't get
out of a hole that you're looking for
something to park your money while you
figure out a plan. In his case, Bitcoin
went higher and allowed him to do what
he's done with strategy, but that's why
most people think this is a scam. In my
opinion,
5 years from now, almost every business
will be in strategy MicroStrategy
situation where they will be competing
against the basement and they will be
competing against the pressures of
competitive companies, but these will be
AI native businesses of which there will
be hundreds of millions if not billions
of them because one person with an AI
agent can set up 100 businesses. It
That's the problem is that the scale of
competition goes through the roof and so
the investment gets into where will
people put a store of value where my
money is going to be worth more than it
is today 3 years from now? That's
getting harder and harder every year
that we go forward.
>> Other than Bitcoin, what else falls in
that category for you?
>> I I I Again, I don't know what can be
worth more in 3 years from now. In my in
my store of value view, I I mean, I
would guess I would select gold just
because as much as Bitcoin would be
there, it's a store of value.
Uh I I think the hardest thing for
people's going to be if the deflationary
pressures of AI get to the point that we
all believe I mean, I know that you and
I believe that that it will. At some
point, the deflationary pressures
destroy all businesses and all assets
because there's no need for the assets
to be worth the value that they are if
everything is heading towards free.
And that's the issue that comes up. I I
think Bitcoin right now because of the
the size of it relative to those 700
trillion,
it really is more of a hedge against
what I'm saying happening than something
that people need to believe in. At some
point, diversification, even at 5%, is
you saying, "I want to have
diversification in real estate and
private equity and private credit and
private public equities." In all of
these different things, I think crypto
needs to be 5%, and 3 years from now, I
don't know if Ethereum is safe on that.
I don't know if Solana is safe on that.
I don't know if Sui is. I don't know if
BitTensor is. I don't know because the
ideas are going to keep coming faster
and faster from AI. So, I want to have
something that has is not built on
ideas. It on beliefs of people believing
that it's a store value. That gets into
gold and that gets into Bitcoin.
>> You previously have talked about
Ethereum, and that seems to be
outperforming Bitcoin. What's going on
there?
>> Again, I This is a big part of why I'm
I'm
I'm adding uh
at least two times a month a
crypto-focused
YouTube. And the reason is because I
believe the ecosystem is growing.
Despite all the
fears and worries over the Clarity Act.
Despite everything going on,
the ecosystem of my 40-name index is
based on the energy that's happening
inside the ecosystem. And that gets back
into AI agents. That gets back into the
amount of volumes and transactions. I
like looking for a variety of signals
that are,
you know, creating a mosaic that this is
happening. Part of them is Ethereum over
Bitcoin. It's saying that the ecosystem,
the network effects are kicking in. Part
of this is how my 40-name basket is
doing, which is outperforming Bitcoin at
this point. So, it's not just Ethereum,
it's the eight verticals or sectors
within inside crypto that are equal
weight that are outperforming Bitcoin.
You've got Stripe heavily involved in
looking to make takeovers of companies
involved with transactions and volumes.
So, for me, that is a signal that,
despite all the doom and gloom,
that we AI is finally starting to kick
into the agentic side. It should match
up with meta.
It should match up with Siri. It should
match up with Alexa, meaning once
consumer agents become real,
the explosion in volume and transactions
should go through the roof, and that's
where the financial guardrails matter.
So, think of Ethereum for me as
the asset that most traditional finance
people that have a lot of money already
know.
And so, it's the safest of the Solanas,
the Suis, wherever you want to go at
this point from the money that matters
that will drive assets, which is the
$700 trillion. They
They chose Bitcoin. That is the store of
value, but the energy side for, "Hey, I
think stablecoins are going to be used
all around the globe, and I think
there's going to be more adoption, and I
think consumer agents are coming. I
think Ethereum's going to benefit the
most."
>> When
you mentioned BitTensor, that seems to
be the thing that is most AI crypto
overlap. Have you spent time on that?
>> Not enough. Um one of the things I'm
doing as part of being ready, and the
reason I keep saying September, early
October,
is because I have to be able to answer
these questions in a way. I'm never
going to be a bottoms-up person all over
things, but I need to understand
how all of the AI agent parts of crypto
fit in. How they fit into what should
happen. So, I've spent a decent amount
of time, but not enough that I want to
start having conversations about it
because part of being
I I spent a lot of time on deep dives. I
mean,
we won't talk about this, I'm sure, this
week, and I don't know if you've seen
it, but Ezra Klein had an interview with
uh Kevin Rudd, who's the former Prime
Minister of Australia.
Kevin Rudd is Kevin Rudd is kind of
world-renowned at this point for
his knowledge of Xi Jinping.
And because China and their open-source
plan is so important to investors,
I know China really well. I traveled
there for a month a year. So, one month
out of every year from 2007 to 2012, I
was in China.
And I got to understand the culture. I
got to understand things from a
grassroots roots perspective. And you
really start to realize that most of
what you hear in the Western media is
not true. And you want to understand
more. Well, Kevin Rudd in this interview
with Ezra Klein really went through what
their AI plan is. How they're thinking
about things.
And a lot of it gets into the K-shaped
economy of the Western world. A lot of
it gets into their beliefs on on Lenin
and Marx and what we're seeing and they
believe that socialism is going to rise
here because of the K-shaped economy.
So, he talked a lot about this and where
it fits in. And the reason I bring this
up to your BitTensor question,
I need to do research on things before I
want to talk about them. I connect dots
really well. Um things that I knew in
the past all of a sudden pop up. And in
the case of this China thing, listening
to Ezra Klein interview Kevin Rudd, I
had a greater appreciation for the plan
that China has in place. What that means
for what David Friedberg talked about on
the All-In podcast with this molecules
to bits and how China basically owns the
manufacturing already. They own this.
Well, this is all part of their
long-term plan. But to hear it presented
in a way that is best for their economy
and navigating their own situation,
which is how do we make sure that we
don't have a big problem here even
though college kids are having a tough
time getting jobs, entrepreneurs are
having a hard time making money, and the
housing market is not going up. To hear
him talk about it in the AI context was
very important. So, once I've done the
same thing on BitTensor and I've
listened to 10 Kevin Rudds give me their
opinion on their business and where it
fits in, I'll be better in a position to
answer.
>> Today's episode is brought to you by
Arch Public. Arch Public has just
expanded its agentic trading platform
beyond crypto. So, pay attention. This
is a big one. Now, they are automating
strategies across stocks, commodities,
and ETFs, and I think that this is going
to be huge. You can now automatically
take profits when one market hits new
all-time highs and rotate that capital
into other markets showing more
opportunity. Whether you're rotating
capital into AI stocks, gold, if you're
investing in the S&P 500, or you're
accumulating Bitcoin, Or Public brings
real discipline and automation to your
investment strategy. Additionally,
they've launched a powerful new tax loss
harvesting tool. With crypto being so
volatile and its exemption from the wash
sale rule, Or Public can offset gains
with losses without compromising your
long-term positions. It's exactly what
every serious investor does.
Institutional grade automation that
works across every major asset class.
There's no more emotional trading, no
more missing tax opportunities, just
smarter, hands-free execution of your
preferred strategies. Go to orpublic.com
right now. Connect with their team, set
up a time, bring your account in if
you'd like, then you can learn what
automated trading can do for you.
orpublic.com.
>> Um this is uh speaking of connecting
dots. One thing I've been thinking about
and um
maybe I'll pose this question to you and
to the audience and then next week we
can come back and talk about maybe some
conclusions we have. But um I was
watching, I don't know if you've seen
these videos of uh
um the migrants in Spain. And there's
basically, you know, thousands, tens of
thousands of people who are coming on
shore. And I'm not an expert on Spain or
the policies or or whatever, but it's a
it's a pretty um
jarring video when you see this.
And what it made me think about was
immigration to the United States used to
happen on boats where people would come
over and they pretty much could bring
whatever they could carry. That was, you
know, kind of the the assets that you
could bring with you. And there were
stories of, you know, people uh getting
on trains and uh people confiscating the
gold at the train station or, you know,
like all of these different kind of
things, right?
Now though, when money moves digital,
there's a very different,
um,
kind of what can you bring with you? But
then vice versa, what can you send back?
And we know remittances are huge, you
know, outside the United leaving the
United States or leaving some of these
countries going back into places where
immigrants are coming from.
And so, what I don't yet have a strong
opinion on is how important is some of
the migration patterns and some and some
of these things that we're seeing that I
think a lot of people look through a
political lens,
but actually in a weird way, the
financial rails being digitized, the
markets being opened
is empowering a participation that
historically wasn't there. You know, you
you you would have to get physical
dollars or or currency, you'd have to
get gold, like these things that just no
longer exist. It does feel like that is
part of the crypto story, that is part
of the digital rail story,
uh, etc.
It's just not, you know, tokenization
and Hayes, NYSE or Nasdaq going to win,
right? It's much more kind of like on
the ground actual people using this
stuff in a way that maybe people in
America don't quite yet understand.
>> Yeah,
so
you left one thing out and again, I'm I
I
I only do this because I spend so much
time on this connection. So, everything
you said is true.
Um,
by having digital currency, by having
the ability to move things easily to go
through it, borders are going to break
down by definition. Um, the capitalist
the the financial guardrails are
changing,
but the part that is different, if you
go through why people would leave a
country and go to another place. And
let's leave out the debasement cuz now
you have the ability of hiding your
money in something that doesn't debase.
So, if you want to stay in Argentina and
the currency is devaluing 50% a year,
you just put your money in stable coins,
dollar stable coins, you're fine. Like,
you couldn't do that while I was in
Brazil. You had to go to a black market
and do that. So, we've already kind of
resolved that.
The other thing is,
if you wanted to hire educated people
and run a business, get an education,
that was the reason why people came to
America. You wanted to get an education
here, then you would stay here, you have
a big labor force that's educated. If
you were from Brazil, there just wasn't
enough educated people to kind of build
a business the same way. And so,
what has changed with AI connected to
crypto is now you can build a business
with no people. You have the cloud you
have platforms, so you can sell your
product globally, anywhere you want, and
can have the money come in in stable
coins. You pay the local tax, Stripe
does all this stuff for you. Everything
has made it easier for you to live
anywhere and run a business. You don't
have to grow it needing to go to school
to certain place. You can use AI to lose
learn whatever you want. You can hire AI
agents so that we don't have to find
smart
This is where we're going is that to me
borders are breaking down. And a person
I've mentioned to you that's a good
friend is Marco Papic, and he wrote a
paper on the metaverse back in 2021.
Now, it happened to coincide with the
crypt the crypto peak and the metaverse
peak, but a lot of what he wrote in
there as a geo macro person was 100%
true. Cuz then you start getting into
well, if the metaverse exists, then
aren't all borders breaking down over
time? And so, I do believe you're losing
some of it. You never lose the
nationalism of people loving their
country and where they were born, but it
does change the fact that over time I
think less people are going to need to
leave anything and they can do whatever
they want financially, transaction-wise,
from a location, and going anywhere will
be easier because
you'll be able to virtually go anywhere
anyway. So, all of this stuff with
borders and countries is going to become
more fragmented and people's views on
are going to change over time.
>> Yeah, in metaverse thing's are so funny
to me. Um, I was never
uh
a big believer in what I call like um
the video game metaverse. Kind of the
like we're all going to have avatars and
you know, that that type of thing. I I
just for whatever reason never really
was like that's going to be the the
future. But what I used to talk about is
like you and I are hanging out in the
metaverse right now.
Right? We are talking at um in a way
where we can be ourselves to a meeting
on the internet. And we don't have to be
together. We can do it in real time and
then we're able to we could be live and
you could have people all around the
world watching. Or you can record it and
post it and you know, watch later. So I
I think that the concept maybe to your
point of the metaverse or or kind of
this like digital uh world is definitely
already happened. I wouldn't even argue
that it's going to happen. It's already
happened. We you know, Zoom and and
Twitter and you all these things.
At the same time, I don't know how much
of it is like the you know, cartoon
avatars and and that whole thing. I
think maybe people have gotten a little
bit more sour on and then probably
rightfully so.
>> Anyone that is a child the same age as
my son, so
has gone through two phenomena. One is
the crypto side during COVID where it
just took off.
But before that, Fortnite.
And Fortnite was a very metaverse thing.
You're playing a video game and it grew
rapidly from zero, I mean it was the
fastest growing video game in history.
And we all had that thing of hearing our
son or daughter playing this game in a
room screaming and they were talking to
friends online playing the game at the
exact same time with the headphone on.
Like this has already happened. That
used to be, you know, me running around
playing fort outside. My mom was like
get out of the house, go run around the
backyard. This was happening virtually.
Um the crypto side, my son traded
aggressively at 13 years old and made a
lot of money and lost a lot of money.
Something that Leopold just did at 25,
he's barely older than my son. My son
has already accomplished what Leopold
did blowing up and leverage and getting
involved in crypto and going up and
down.
But there was something else that
happened that I've mentioned before.
The Philippines went through an economic
change because of Axi Infinity. And for
any of you watching that have never read
about Axi Infinity, go bring up a
YouTube documentary. I know there's a
bunch out there. There's one that's 30
minutes.
It impacted the entire economy of the
Philippines. So,
that is another form of metaverse. That
is gaming meets the economics. It was
all about gambling. It was all about a
video game. It was like Fortnite, but it
was pay-to-play and it was having an
impact on the economy and I
my son played it for one day and said he
could never win because they were too
good. That is the world I absolutely
believe we're heading towards. The only
reason it hasn't happened yet,
crypto and the ideas are still good.
They're still all of the entrepreneurs
that came up with these things.
It's going to happen. When I hear Candy
Digital and I realize as a sports fan
that that scenario of a sports and the
memories you have being valuable, being
at a game, the dunk. You already have a
painting of OG
that I saw in your office,
that moment in time I'll never forget.
I'll never forget where I was. I'll
never forget being under the basket for
that and the people I was with. I'll
never forget that even if I never see
them again. So, I think people have to
realize that the world that you're
describing, this virtual world, virtual
money, all of these things, they're
happening.
And it's owned the money of the world,
the 700 trillion is owned predominantly
by people that are baby boomers and
people that are above the age of 60. As
the demographic shifts, these younger
people like my son, like Leopold, they
believe in this type of
I hate to say it, balls-to-the-wall type
approach. The entertainment is coming
from living life and going through the
ups and downs and virtually traveling
and all of this. It's a different world
and I think it's going to remain a
different world for a long time.
>> I love it. I mean, why not why not live
life that way versus be bored, you know?
>> That's why I'm in Maine, my friend.
>> [laughter]
>> All right. What
what what are you going to cover in your
video this week? For anyone who goes go
on YouTube and just search Jordy Visser,
go check out the video that he puts out
on Sunday morning. But what what are you
going to cover this week?
>> So, I'm going to go through the the
Leopold situation. I'm going to go
through the details on the factor moves,
the market structure change,
and then I mean, again, I think people
based on my subscribers and based on the
people that are involved with me on a
regular basis, I had to do four videos
in true, you know, four this month on
top of the four that I already do for
the subscribers,
because during these months, it gets
very nerve-racking and you're more prone
to making emotional decisions. I'm going
to cover why I think the bottom is in
for the AI trade and why people should
be going through I'm I'm going to show
how I've created report called Combing
Through the Carnage to go through all of
the details and which names at this
point technically didn't break down.
They've reset and as my father used to
say, if in May the odds on the AI trade
working were one to two and you were
barely getting any payoff over the next
6 months,
you'll be shocked right now that with
the correction we've had, which is still
in a bull market, we're still above
moving averages,
the odds have now gone back to three to
one on a lot of things. So, I mentioned
last week that I bought Micron
or 2 weeks ago. Well, I got chance to
buy a little bit lower and as I said,
these were nibbles. Now I feel more
comfortable buying into weakness rather
than just buying strength. I don't think
we're zooming right to the top of
things. I think there's going to be more
of a more liquidations coming
particularly in the first week of
August, but I do think that the Leopold
situation ended up getting a tremendous
amount of sell pressure. So, I'm going
to go through that, my experience on
those, and
we'll cover it all this weekend.
>> Amazing. All right, Jordy. Thank you
very much. We'll talk again next week.
>> Thanks, bud. Have a good one.